

Jomar B. Herrera

Al Satwa, Dubai, UAE • Phone: 056 344 0350 • jomar.herrera@yahoo.com

Accounting Professional

I consider myself a versatile, productive worker with a solid work ethic who exerts optimal effort to ensure all tasks are completed on time and to the highest standards. I carry a dynamic, results-oriented skill with the ability to easily grasp and put into application new ideas, concepts, and methods and equipped with the following:

- A way with numbers I like working with facts and figures
- A passion for detail I am naturally precise
- A love of solitude I love working in a group or in an environment where the nature of the work does not promote a lot of social interaction or togetherness.

I have more than 10 years of experience in accounting sector. I initially worked in Accenture (Philippines) where I have been exposed to a fast-paced and challenging atmosphere. With my positive 'can do' attitude, I continued my career in different local offices to gain broad experience in bookkeeping, tax, accounting, and audit.

After qualifying my experience, I joined Maersk Group. I started in Maersk Filipinas and moved to Maersk GSC for different accounting responsibilities. My major role was focused on SAP process mapping & alignment, transferring knowledge-based Finance and Accounting processes and delivering successful project execution.

A combination of my natural ability, technical expertise and work experience made me an ideal candidate in different companies where I was given a busy role in implementing a system, developing process improvements and aligning the process to the new accounting system.

My biggest accomplishment was my role as a Business Process Expert in Maersk Group where I was given cross-country assignments abroad and exposure in supervising a team size covering more than 40 goal-driven people.

Skills

Financial Accounting, Analysis and Reporting Project Management and Process Improvement Creative Team Leadership SAP Process Mapping & Alignment Organizational Skills, Time Management, Adaptability, Communication, and Openness

Technology

Software: SAP, QuickBooks, MYOB, MS Office (Word, Access, Excel, PowerPoint)

Personal Background

Visa Status : Visit Visa
Age : 32 years old
Marital Status : Single
Gender : Male

Birthday : January 5, 1984
Birthplace : Philippines

Nationality : Filipino

Languages Spoken : English, Tagalog

Education

CITY UNIVERSITY OF PASAY, Philippines Bachelor of Science, April 2005

Field: Accountancy Major: Accounting

Professional Experience

DB SCHENKER PHILIPPINES – the subsidiary of DB Schenker AG that provides integrated transportation, logistics and supply chain solutions in the Philippines

Budget Accountant and Internal Audit Assistant, Nov 2015 → Mar 2016

Managed and analyzed transactions of the company that includes both purchases/gen. expenses and earnings/sales income. Implemented accounting systems to ensure the transactions and overall finances are maintained in a consistent manner. Analyzed each department's budget to ensure availability of funds for monthly operations by consulting with the Dept. Managers to see how budget adjustments can save funds during a single month to stay on track.

Audited the annual report that reflects the past year's financial status and checked if the annual report includes budgets for all of the expenses, purchases and salaries paid to keep the business operative, and all of the income statements that show how much the company has earned.

DEAN AND DELUCA (PHILIPPINES) • A franchised restaurant of Dean and Deluca (New York) that deals on retail, café setups and catering services.

General Accountant, Jun 2015 → Nov 2015

Prepared asset, liability, and capital account entries by compiling and analyzing account information

Documented financial transactions by entering account information

Recommended financial actions by analyzing accounting options

Summarized financial status by collecting information; preparing balance sheet, profit & loss statement, and other reports Substantiated financial transactions by auditing documents

Maintained accounting controls by preparing and recommending policies and procedures

Guided accounting clerical staff by coordinating activities and answering questions

Reconciled financial discrepancies by collecting and analyzing account information

Prepared payments by verifying documentation, and requesting disbursements

Answered accounting procedure questions by researching and interpreting accounting policy and regulations

Prepared special financial reports by collecting, analyzing, and summarizing account information and trends

Maintained customer confidence and protected operations by keeping financial information confidential.

Maintained professional and technical knowledge by attending educational workshops; reviewing professional publications;

establishing personal networks; participating in professional societies

Contributed to team effort by accomplishing related results as needed

Slashed payroll/benefits administrations costs by negotiating pricing and fees

FLUOR PHILIPPINES – A subsidiary of Fluor Corporation, a FORTUNE 500 company that delivers engineering, procurement, construction, maintenance, and project management to governments and clients in diverse industries around the world. **In-House General Accountant,** May 2012 ➡ May 2015

Initiated a Unit/Key person to streamline operations and improve customer service. Program was rolled out company-wide based on initial success.

Sponsored divisional rewards and goal alignment team to improve employee retention and job satisfaction

Directed weekly and monthly meetings and set performance milestones to ensure accuracy and timeliness of month-end deliverables.

Reviewed and continuously improved processes to increase efficiency and quality of process flow.

Created accounting control system to support growth of staffs at no increase in cost.

Presented recommendations to leverage the services, improve operations and increase revenues.

Worked closely with the Finance Manager and other Senior Executives to develop marketing programs.

MAERSK GLOBAL SERVICE CENTRES (PHILS) LTD – the shared service center of A.P. Moller Maersk Group that provides offshoring opportunities and solutions to the business units of Maersk Line, the world sa largest container shipping company. Business Process Expert / Assistant to the Team Leader, Mar 2008 ⇒ Apr 2012

Mitigated risks and/or issue recurrence by serving as the escalation point/first level support for customer complaints and complex SAP technical issues through gathering data from end users, investigating the issues and formulating root cause analysis and preventive measures.

Reduced system variations by developing and implementing SOP through defining the procedures to meet the requirements needed and engaging the team to generate positive ideas, feel a sense of ownership in it and reduce system variations. Improved employee performance and satisfaction and reduced weak links in a team by spearheading relevant trainings on new functionalities introduced in the SAP system, conducting an appropriate knowledge-sharing sessions to staffs, and cascading changes in the global SOPs & their corresponding impact in the business processes.

Anchored the implementation of process improvement tools by defining the scope of the problem; reviewing and understanding the current situation and background; identifying improvements or solutions to the problem; verifying if the improvements will bring about benefits that meet the defined success criteria; and executing implementation of the solutions and improvements.

MULTIPLE COMPANIES | PHILIPPINES → Accounting Role

Worked in different companies from 2005-2008 to consummate my skills and flair in different accounting fields.